# Crystal Yan 408.899.96711 yan.crystal.c@gmail.com

Product management and design leader focused on transforming organizations to become more customer-centric. Experience using behavioral science and artificial intelligence to create meaningful user experiences for B2B and B2C products globally.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Product Manager & Product Design Manager — FiscalNote, Washington, DC MAR 2016 - PRESENT

- Hiring manager reporting directly to COO/VP of Product, responsible for designing interview process, interviewing, onboarding and training new product managers and designers.
- Set the vision and roadmap of product portfolio generating > \$8M annual recurring revenue (ARR). Develop new product lines for web and mobile, including EU, South America and Asia product offerings for C-suite buyer personas. Led product vision that landed first enterprise client with total contract value (TCV) that increased company revenue by 10%.
- Lead the full-stack design discovery process: conduct qualitative and quantitative user experience (UX) research with interviews and metrics analysis; lead ideation and wireframing; create interactive high-fidelity prototypes, and test with users to validate hypotheses.
- Lead delivery sprints with engineering and QA; Develop UI asset and UX pattern library.
- · Plan and execute on go-to-market strategy with marketing, sales, and client success teams for new releases that grew average contract value (ACV) from 43.54% from 2015 Q4 to 2016 Q3.

## Freelance Designer & Product Strategy Consultant — Independent, Remote AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- UX Design Lead for MyHealthEd, Inc, a nonprofit transforming sex education with storytelling. Leading the UX and interaction design for an app for 13-14 year old low-income teens. Following our engagement, MHE launched their first beta and raised an additional \$50K in funding.
- Curriculum Design Consultant for the DC Mayor's Office Summer Youth Employment Program. • Design Lead for Rise, a civil rights NGO advocating for a Sexual Assault Survivors' Bill of Rights.

# Associate Product Manager & Associate UX Researcher/Designer — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- Launched company's first iOS app: Produced hi-fidelity prototypes, ran usability testing, started a client beta testing program, iterated designs based on user feedback, and worked with 2 mobile engineers to launch product to a downloadable app in the App Store in four months.
- · Aligned heads of product, sales, client success, and marketing on user personas that guide everything from product strategy to employee onboarding to marketing campaign targeting.
- Designed the first copywriting and UX design style guide for the frontend engineering team.

# **Business Development Associate** — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- Third revenue hire. Interim Head of Marketing for 4 months. Advised VPs with demos to close deals and achieve product-market fit, contributing to company raising \$18 million in funding.
- · Consistently hit but often exceeded monthly quotas; closed \$386,842 in new revenue with shortest sales cycles. Brought on new clients: Uber, Lyft, FireEye, Akin Gump, and Coinbase.
- Led onboarding sessions for 35+ new hires, trained reps on optimal ways to structure pricing and contract terms in order to maximize ACV and improve cash flow; ACV grew 76.82%.

# User Experience Researcher—Innovation Works, Beijing, China

OCT 2012 - DEC 2013

· Led a corporate development strategy & operations project in the user experience department for China's premier early-stage investment fund for technology startups

### Product Manager - Mobile, Standard Chartered Bank, Shanghai, China AUG 2012 - SEP 2012

- · Led product development & user testing for bilingual iPad app (English/Mandarin) targeting small business owners, increasing customer leads and reducing product support costs
- Analyzed vendor supplier data to identify excess expenses, cut development costs by 27%

### **SKILLS**

### Management:

Interviewing, Hiring, Onboarding, Training, Leading **Design Sprints** User Research: Data Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, User Testing **Design:** Interaction, UI & Visual (Sketch, Adobe CS), Mobile, Prototyping (InVision)

#### **SPEAKING**

StarsConf 2017

Santiago, Chile RubyConf 2017 Medellin, Colombia **Grace Hopper 2017** Orlando, FL **Scenic City Summit** Chattanooga, TN **UXDC 2017** Washington, DC **ULLConf 2016** Killarney, Ireland AIGA DotGovDesign Washington, DC Microsoft Research Beijing, China

### **EDUCATION**

**Amherst College** BA, Economics, 2014 **Tsinghua University** International Affairs Beijing, Fall 2012 **International Honors Program Urban Planning &** Anthropology Delhi, Dakar, Buenos Aires, Spring 2013